■ duyo@ualberta.ca 4780-907-0945 • Calgary, AB daniel-uyo • the Uyonator

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in frontend, backend, and full stack web development, proficient in the use of various programming languages and frameworks including JavaScript, Python, Flask, SQL, Node.js, Express, React, Redux etc. Also possesses project management experience from previously held positions as a project engineer.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### React-Shoply - A Frontend Ecommerce Admin Dashboard

- A Frontend Ecommerce Admin Dashboard complete with 5 different sales analytics charts, Kanban, calendar, product log etc.
- Tools & Libraries: React, Tailwind, Syncfusion
- The purpose of this app is to showcase a well rounded and beautifully designed frontend ecommerce application with modern components like built using Syncfusion

## **Cryble** - A cryptocurrency encyclopedia

- A cryptocurrency dictionary / library built on Node.js and React, displaying the top 100 cryptocurrencies in the world, related recent news
  articles, exchanges, historical data and background information on individual cryptocurrencies
- Tools & Libraries: React, Redux, Node.js, PostgreSQL, moment.js, Ant Design, charts.js, Jest, RESTful Apis, Git, GitHub etc.
- The infrastructure of this project was decided according to what information would be relevant to new cryptocurrency researchers and what APIs could provide that information
- Data on cryptocurrencies were retrieved using the Coinranking API and recent news articles retrieved using the Bing News Search API, both on Rapid Api Hub

## <u>dateMeet</u> - A social media business locator app

- A social media app that allows users to search for up to 100 local businesses by their interests and leave recommendations on these businesses
- Tools & Libraries: JavaScript, AJAX, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL etc.
- The infrastructure of this app was decided based on the user entered location, using this location, the user will be able to search for near-by business according and interests and provide recommendations in their location
- Google's Geocoding API was used to validate user location and Yelp Fusion API was used to retrieve top 100 businesses around the saved user location

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Technology Consultant | Accenture | Calgary, AB

Sep 2021 - Present

- Leading and implementing the latest technological advancements and solutions for various clients and in varying industries including oil & gas, software and technology, manufacturing etc.
- Performing analyses on hardware, software, network, security, and project delivery capabilities and advising on ways to increase these capabilities by up to 30%
- Documenting processes and monitoring system performance and metrics
- Combining analytics-based insights with expertise and experience to connect the end-to-end capabilities needed to drive change for any given client

# Software Engineering Fellow | Springboard | Calgary, AB

Nov 2020 - Dec 2021

- Utilizing more than 10 programming languages and frameworks like JavaScript, Python, React, Node.js etc. to create frontend, backend, and full stack applications
- Building full CRUD web apps, utilizing different API platforms to retrieve relevant information, and displaying them in a fashion that enhances the user experience
- Performing debugging and testing on simple and complex code to produce fully functional web applications
- Solving complex data and algorithm problems with efficiency and scalability in mind, providing more efficient solutions where possible

## Mechanical Engineer | Worley Engineering Services | Edmonton, AB

Sep 2018 - Sep 2021

- Produced more than 100 design documentation and deliverables including equipment sizing calculations, data sheets, equipment lists etc.
- Performed analysis, calculations, and various engineering studies to increase production by up to 20% and reduce error by more than 10%
- Collaborated with a variety of engineering disciplines to achieve efficient engineering solutions
- Compiled construction work packages, material requisitions etc. detailing efficient ways to exceed client expectation while cutting cost by more than 10%

# **EDUCATION**